Hey, what's up everybody? I almost
didn't make this video because I wasn't
sure if I could do it justice, but I'm I
want to share with you a concept that I
think is going to change your life if
you apply it. If you have been in the
personal development space for a while,
you've learned things on mindset and
what to do with how you think and how
you do things. You know that there's a
ton of different information out there.
There's a ton of different opinions on
how we should be doing stuff like that.
I've been in the personal development
space for a long time. And for those of
you that I haven't met yet, my name is
Jeremiah Kowski. I have been building
businesses for 23 years in the online
marketing, personal development,
coaching space. During that time, again,
I got my start helping business owners
and sales trainers and building my own
businesses over $160,000 a month, over
seven figures in business that we make
in our business here today. Now, what I
want to show you is how to get your
mindset to align with the goals and
dreams that you have. Now, my life
story, I you don't want to hear the drag
of my life story. Honestly, it's not
been as bad as a lot of people, I would
say, but I've had my own ups and downs.
And I'll tell you that just I was raised
in an environment that prioritized it.
It it it created the perfect storm to
create somebody who drank a lot of
alcohol, tried to run away from their
feelings, and lived by performance,
lived by feeling like I was never good
enough. And what that did did for me is
it drove me one, it it it drove me to
build businesses to be successful. But
number two, if things weren't perfect,
perfectionism,
I would crumble. And so what I want to
share with you is coming out of that,
what I've learned over the years of
going through personal development and
all of that. And then a strategy that
I've recently learned that works better
than anything else that I've learned
over those years. That's what I want to
share with you is this strategy. You
know, we know about therapy. We know
about finding what is the root cause of
why we're dealing with issues and things
like that. But here's the new strategy
that I found that has helped is is that
when you are experiencing something that
is blocking you, well, first let's go
back to this this fact. Number one, and
I I I used to talk about this a lot a
couple years ago in my podcast.
Your decisions in your life determine
your outcomes. Whatever you're getting,
whatever you are experiencing, whatever
even triggers you have are coming from
decisions and beliefs that you've made.
A belief creates a decision. And so how
we show up is based on how those beliefs
string together.
Okay? how we experience life, how we
show up in our business. And so if I'm
finding that I'm struggling
because I get overwhelmed or triggered
to build my business or I'm experiencing
this in my family life. It's tied to
beliefs that then lead into decisions
that are dominating my thought space and
they're impacting my nervous system in a
powerful way. And so there's two states
of being that we often live in as
people. I I if you study polyagal
theory, you'll learn about the the three
kind of different states. You have the
um the rest and digest space, uh
parasympathetic, and then we have the
freeze response. And so we have fight or
flight, we have freeze, and then we have
kind of a a peaceful thriving state of
mind. And so that state of our not even
just mind but nervous system when we're
in that thriving state we're not in
fight flight or freeze is where our
creativity comes from. It's where our
best ideas flow from. It's where we can
show up at our best to impact the world
around us and to do the things that
we're called and meant to do.
One of the things that I found is that
oftentimes
we can we go back and forth between
these and that's a normal part of life.
We don't want to stuff them. We don't
want to disappear from our feelings. But
what we want to do is we want to learn
how can I get back to that place of
thriving. Another sense to call it would
be our sort of a primal state. That's
the fight, flight, or freeze. It's like
the the the sort of brain that's deep in
the recesses of it's it's it's almost
uncontrollable. It's a feeling and it's
starting to to run our nervous system
because again fight, flight or freeze
is something that we don't control as it
happens. Somebody cuts you off in
traffic and you immediately get angry or
you get nervous or scared. Somebody
starts threatening you and you start
getting scared. That fear and worry is
that automatic response. But what we can
do is based in our beliefs and
decisions, we can decide how it actually
affects us and we can then come out of
those states. We experience them all the
time as people. It happens. And you
don't want to turn that off. I used to
think that you want to turn those things
off. You don't want to. You you actually
want to learn how to control your
nervous system to be able to give you
the kind of reactions that you want and
to move from one into another. So if I
get into fight, flight or freeze, okay,
what's my belief about that?
And then how can I shift into the place
where I want to be? A great example of
this would be again I grew up where
performance was a big factor in my life
and and what I had to do to be able to
be to feel like I was worthy of love and
success. And then what ends up happening
is I'm married. I got two kids. And then
I might drop the ball in my in my
marriage. my wife is disappointed in
something and if I just shut down or I
get angry as an automatic response,
neither of those work. And this is what
I had to train myself because it was
literally hurting my life, my marriage,
and my business to where I would have
these automatic responses that came from
these childhood
experiences. And even going through
years and years of therapy, I wasn't
finding that it was working to change a
lot of those responses until I looked at
these decisions and beliefs that I had.
And so what I had to look at was this.
And this is the powerful thing. It's a
powerful way to reframe
what you believe to be able to change
your life is if you look at, okay, what
am I experiencing right now? What is
that trigger? What is that moment that's
happening? Let's say you go to build
your business and to to write an email.
I'm going to give you an example of
something that my clients experience and
that that even I've experienced. You go
to write a marketing email and you
immediately start getting tired and
exhausted.
You start feeling like, gosh, this is so
difficult for me to do right now. Gosh,
this is so hard for me to do to be able
to write this email. I don't I don't
want to I don't want to write it wrong
or things like that. Well, there's
beliefs in the subconscious
that start to create that trigger that
are then creating the nervous system
response of tired protection, self-p
protection in that moment. And that's
usually what ends up happening when we
end up having fatigue about doing
certain things in our business. When we
start going to do things in our business
and then we feel fatigued in that
moment. It's not necessarily actually
that we're fatigued in a big way. It's
actually that there's a belief behind it
that we're trying to block out or get
rid of. Or maybe you see that you have
mountains of piling debt. What does that
mean about you when you look at that?
And so what we have to do is this is we
have to look at what is that belief
that's bes that's behind
that decision that I'm making. Okay. So
what is the belief about the email is
well I don't want to write something
that's not going to necessarily work or
produce the result that I want. The
email has to be perfect to produ to
produce the result that I want or it's
not worth it. And so we now have a
belief that I get the results that I
want in my life when I do everything
perfect.
And so what ends up happening is is that
because we don't know if it's perfect or
not. Oftentimes when it comes to online
marketing or building our business, we
don't know if what we're doing is
perfect or not. Even recording a video
like this, I don't know if it's perfect.
It's probably not perfect. It's probably
it's probably got a bunch of mistakes
and errors and I'm saying things wrong.
But it's okay. It's okay because I have
a belief that it's okay that things
actually work out well even when they
are imperfect.
And so what I've had to do is I've had
to reframe that. So I look at the emails
and I say, "Okay,
that's the decision that I have that's
creating that that that fatigue
possibly. I'm either worried about how
people are going to perceive me or what
they're going to think about me." And I
start to question, is it good enough to
put this out there?
And then by questioning that, I end up
showing up
as this lesser version of myself. Not
that I'm lesser, but I'm less powerful
in this. That I'm now procrastinating to
create my emails. I'm now putting off
the things that I know that I need to do
to build my funnel in my marketing and
in my business. And so then what I have
to do is this is I have to look at it
and I and I have to say, okay, what is
that belief that's beneath the surface?
And then what is the opposite of that
belief? And this is where it is. we
start refraraming these beliefs in our
minds. And there's a twopart process to
this that makes it life-changing. The
the first part is going to feel like
you're lying to yourself. This is where
affirmations often go wrong. I'm going
to affirm. I'm a great leader. I'm a
powerful husband. All this. And then the
next day, you know, you just you fail.
But what ends up happening is is this is
that if you can find a belief that's the
opposite of the thing that you're
experiencing.
Like I don't have to be perfect to be
trusted or respected by others. That was
a hard one for me to learn. I had to
literally reframe that because I had a
belief that for other people to trust
me, I had to be perfect in how I showed
up. And if I wasn't perfect, nobody
would trust me to do business enough
with me. And it was creating this
scenario in my life where I literally
was not showing up in my business the
way that I needed to because I felt like
I had to be perfect. And so the reframe
of it is this is that people can trust
me even if I'm not perfect, even if I
show up authentically or imperfectly or
make mistakes.
And now my mind starts telling me, well,
that's not necessarily true. It starts
calling BS on this. And this is where we
got to shift it. Is what is the evidence
in my life that I've experienced? And
sometimes it it took me all day to
actually find this one. What is the
evidence in my life? Sometimes it can
take you 24 hours. You got to go to
sleep and you got to remind yourself of
what these beliefs are.
What is the evidence in my life
that I can be trusted by people even
when I'm imperfect? Even when I might
make a typo in an email? Even if I I
might not say it right, even if I might
not do everything perfect, even if I
might not articulate myself perfectly to
people,
what is that proof of that in my life
where that's happened for me?
And I start to find my brain starts to
go to work finding evidence
for the fact that that's happened.
And then what you can do is once you
start to find the evidence, here's what
ends up happening. your brain starts to
believe the new belief because now it
has evidence for it. And this is
powerful. This is a powerful thing where
you you find, okay, what's the trigger?
What's the moment that's stopping me?
What's the behavior that I don't like?
And I and this is and this is actually
the the the process for this. Let me let
me write this on the whiteboard.
Is number one,
what is the outcome that I want? Okay.
What is the outcome that I desire to get
from this? What what is the you got a
you have a trigger,
you have some kind of a nervous system
response,
something that's happening, and then you
have a different outcome that you would
like. Number two
is you have
a belief
which leads to a decision.
Number three, what is the new
opposite
belief?
Could be like it's always it's too hard
to hire people in my business. It's too
hard to manage people to it's easy to
manage people. It's easy to be able to
do this
and then what is the evidence of it that
that you are able to maybe not
necessarily that it's easy to but I can
manage people well I'm a good manager of
people even if if you have not
experienced that a lot what are moments
where you've been a good manager of
people and you find evidence for that
find evidence
in your life or you could find the
evidence in another person's life this
one's a big one especially if you're
looking for something that you've never
done before. And this is where the shift
is. See, we have this thing where we
feel like I have to know everything
before I can do it. And you don't have
to know everything before you can do it.
You don't have to know how to do this
before you can start to implement it.
You could say that the evidence could be
in somebody else's life where they know
how to do it and I could learn from them
in that even. And then number five,
we end up attaching it to gratitude.
I'm grateful for the opportunity for
this new way of doing things and how
this new experience of mine is. And this
is how I'm now going to approach my
life. And then number six
is I like to bring my faith into it
where I believe that I'm guided and even
directed and called by God to experience
that new belief.
And so if you see this framework right
here, this is this is literally a
framework. And I did not I did not
invent this framework. I'll tell you
that. I'll tell you where where actually
I a couple of resources that I learned
it from. I had um a little bit of help
with some chat GPT. There was a book
that I actually read recently and I'm
I'm going to give you the book and I'm
going to tell you to to to check it out
because I think that it's good to to to
share sources where we get good
information is let me let me pull it up
here. I want to pull it up on the screen
so you can actually see it. The book is
called A Changed Mind by David Bayer. Uh
go beyond self-awareness, rewire your
brain and re-engineer your reality. and
he breaks down this exact type of
formula right here and how to do this
and this is how I've now applied it in
my life is being able to do that. So
again would highly recommend that that
that book to you. This is not
necessarily new information. This has
been in the personal development space
for a while. But the way that it's
filtered through where you find the new
outcome that you want that's opposite of
that trigger, that experience, that that
fear, that worry, that insecurity that
you have. And then you identify what is
the belief or decision that's connected
to that.
And then you figure out, okay, what's
the opposite belief of how of what would
create that new outcome for you? Even if
it you don't think it's true. Even if
you're like, "Okay, I'm not sure about
this." And then you go and you find
evidence of moments in your life where
that belief happened for you, where that
new scenario or information happened for
you. You attach gratitude to it. I'm
grateful for the opportunity to do this.
I'm grateful for this new belief. I'm
grateful for the evidence of that this
has happened, for the situation that I'm
in that's allowing me to create this.
And then I love throwing my faith right
on top of that and just wrapping a bow
around it of I am called by God to
experience
this evidence, this belief, this change
in my behavior, in my life to go forward
and to change everything. And so now
when it comes to you building your
business, when it comes to anything that
you have going on in your life, I'll
tell you, I've applied this to literally
everything that I that I've been doing.
this this this
uh this decision matrix right here.
That's what David calls it. David Barry,
the author of that book, the decision
matrix to be able to do that and to be
able to take it and to apply it in my
life. And I'll tell you, that's one of
the key things that that that you can do
to be able to help you. It goes beyond
just I love therapy. I think there's a
lot of great personal development out
there. But if you then apply this
six-step process to that on top of all
the stuff that you've learned over the
years about personal development,
it will catapult you and catalyze you to
be able to get more done than you ever
imagined. Because what is going to
happen is this creates safety in your
life. that new evidence, that new
belief, the gratitude, and having faith
and belief in what you're called to do,
you feel safe
internally. Your whole nervous system
feels safe to be able to go do the
things that you want to do. You know,
another example belief, I'll give you a
couple other examples of how this is.
Maybe you get triggered in in a
relationship or on a sales call with
somebody. I I I struggle to feel
confident when I talk to people that
I've never met before. That's a belief
right there. What if you say, "I'm I'm
confident and and excited when I talk to
people that are new people that I've
never met before." Now, what is the the
evidence of that belief? What moments in
your life when you felt confident
talking to new people? You start to feel
gratitude for that confidence in talking
to new people and how you felt that way
in the past. And that actually my faith
is I'm called by God to talk to new
people all the time because that's what
I'm meant to do to go out there and
accomplish the things that I'm meant to
do in my life.
And maybe it's just I'm called, you
know, if you don't believe in God, you
whatever belief you have a higher power
or something. But I believe that there's
that it's important to attach that to
this. And I think that if you can apply
this in your life, you can apply this in
your business, in your family, in your
relationships. I have seen this
transform my marriage, this process
right here. And again, I'd re I I'd
recommend I I've not necessarily plugged
into any of the other seminars or
anything that that David's done, but I
read this book and I just I thought it
was powerful and I wanted to share this
with you and I wanted to bring this
information to you to be able to show
you this powerful method. I think that
if you start applying this in your life
and you start saying, "Okay, what what
are these things that I can do?" I I
started using chat GPT to even help me
identify what those things are. I
started I started asking it to give me
ideas for what those things are and the
and my uh AI assistant was able to
actually help me identify what those
were. So that then instead of me trying
to rack my brain or figure it out, I'm
like, "Oh, okay. Here's some some of the
limiting beliefs. Here's what the
replacement is here. I could change it.
Here's some necessary statements I could
say to help me with this. And it's
helpful. It's some some helpful stuff
that you can do. Listen, if you're a
business owner and you're somebody that
wants to accomplish greater things, this
is a mindset shift that will change
everything for you. And listen, if you
want to know how to grow your business,
how to grow your wealth, how to increase
your leads, your customers, your
clients, if you're in a service-based
business, you want to know how to use AI
in a powerful way that's going to help
you accomplish anything that you want.
So, you don't have to be a marketing
expert so that you can shift your life
and your business and your income. My
Wealthy Coach Academy program is the
place to do so. Check it out. You can
click one of the links in the
description below. You can check out one
of the classes that we have going on as
well on how to do this. We'll see you
soon. Subscribe to my channel.